in this video we're going to look at the
GP snapshot feature that's part of the
GP Cloud migration tool the GP snapshot
allows you to bring over transactional
information from GP into business
Central in extension tables the data can
be viewed in list Pages Bound in
business Central let's take a closer
look at how you can configure the GP
snapshot Once you walk through the cloud
migration wizard you are presented with
the GP company migration configuration
page
this page can also be navigated to from
the cloud migration management
page if we scroll to the bottom we can
see a section called historical snapshot
you can indicate what module
transactions you would like migrated to
business Central once you select the
module transactions you can indicate how
far back you want to bring over the
transactional data the system will
default in the year that you indicated
for your GL summary however you can
certainly tweak that if you want that to
be different for example you may want to
bring over the last 3 years of GL
summary inform information but maybe you
want to go back seven years for the
snapshot information you simply need to
select and enter in a different year to
bring over the snapshot
data once you complete the information
in the GP company migration
configuration page you can begin the
migration the GP snapshot will run
automatically once the migration is
complete you can monitor the progress of
the snapshot by looking at the tiles in
the cloud migration management
page once the snapshot process is
finished you can view the data in
business
Central next let's look at some of the
snapshot data that was migrated we'll
first begin by viewing GL detail
information to navigate to that we'll go
to the chart of
accounts under the chart of accounts you
can navigate under account and then see
an option for GP detail snapshot there
are two options to select in here they
both show the same data the second one
just organizes the data by the account
number if I go into the all detail
transactions you can see a lot of the
information that was migrated over from
GP to business
Central in here you can see this
information comes from the GP 20,000 and
30,000 tables so that is the detailed
tables in GP for both your open and
history you can see the account numbers
the account string that users are
familiar with in GP as well as the debit
and credit amounts like any list page in
business Central you can export this
information out to excel you can also
filter on it and search for anything so
for example if you were searching for a
specific journal entry number you could
enter that into the search and then the
the page will automatically filter so
you can see these are all the accounts
that were post posted to with the debit
and credit amounts for this journal
entry number if the transaction came
from a subledger you can drill back on
that journal entry number to see that
subledger
transactions in this case this was a
sales orderer processing invoice so at
the top you can see this is the Header
information for my sales transaction and
then down below you can see all the
transaction lines that were associated
with the invoice if any of these items
were track had Seri Lot number tracking
you could drill back on the quantity and
see their serial or lot
information next let's take a look at
customer
transactions if I navigate to my
customer list in business Central there
will be a very similar option that I saw
in the chart of accounts if I navigate
under customer I'll see the same option
GP detail snapshot this is where I can
see my receivables and sales order
processing transactions if I navigate to
the forums through this way I will see
transaction for all customers if however
you want to see transactions for a
specific customer select that customer
for the list and then choose one of the
tiles on the right side I'll go ahead
and select the receivables transactions
now the list will filter to just the
transactions for Aaron Fitz
electrical again you can drill back to
see more information about the
individual transaction so in this case I
can drill back and see that receivables
transaction information I can also see
if any payments were applied to this
invoice so the snapshot will also
include apply information for both
receivables and payables
documents the very same information can
be seen for vendors so if I navigate
under vendors there's another option for
the historical snapshot for your
vendors here I can see my payables
information as well as any purchase
receiving transactions again and if I
navigate through the navigation here I
will see it for all vendors there are
also tiles on the right hand side again
which will filter based on the vendor
selected finally we can see information
about items so if I navigate under items
snapshot information is also brought
over for my inventory transactions since
there isn't tiles for the item list you
can navigate to it only under items and
then the DP GP detail snapshot
and that's a quick look at the GP
snapshot feature that's available in the
GP Cloud migration tool to learn more
about business Central check out the
training modules at
aka.ms slbc learn there are also
additional resources available to
Partners